Md Mehedi Hasan

Mechanical Engineer



United Mymenshing Power Ltd (UMPL) Chorjathartopur, Jamalpur Sadar, Jamalpur.



mehedihme@outlook.com



+8801701-029913



29-04-1997



Married



Almost 6.2 years of work experience in the field of mechanical maintenance after completion of a Diploma In Marine Engineering. Indepth knowledge of all the aspects of functionalities of machines and the major mechanical equipment such as Solar Panels, Inverter, Diesel Generator, Separator and Turbo Charger. Strong problem solving organizational and time management skills. well versed with the legal issues and safety standards to be followed during the work site.



Special Qualification



Commissioning, Operation, Troubleshooting & Maintenance of HFO & LO Separators such as Westfalia and ALFA Laval Separators.

Turbo Charger

Expertise in Turbo Charger Napier (NT 1-12)



Work History

Sr. Assistant Engineer

Mechanical Maintenance, United Mymensingh & Jamalpur Power Ltd. 315 MW Combined Cycle Power Plant.

- Supervise the installation and maintenance of mechanical equipment, such as solar panels, inverters, and tracking systems.
- Design and develop mechanical systems for solar power plants including thermal storage, solar panels, and support structures.
- Develop and implement maintenance procedures to ensure maximum performance and uptime of mechanical systems.
- Condition evaluation and servicing of Turbo Charger and Remove and Re-fitting Turbo Charger.
- Maintaining proper documentation for maintenance of the engine and related auxiliaries.
- Preparing Spare parts and maintenance forecast, inspecting used parts and all documentation of Separators.
- Reducing spare parts consumption through improvisation and in-house repair.
- Conducted root-cause analysis of component failure.
- Developed work plans for various personnel roles based on strengths and talents.

Assistant Engineer

Mechanical Maintenance, United Mymensingh 200 MW Combined Cycle Power Plant.

- To ensure safe scheduled maintenance of 1000, 2000, 4000, 12000 hours schedule maintenance of engine.
- Successfully done 12000 hours schedule maintenance of Wartsila 20V32E Engine.
- Key player in troubleshooting and maintenance of ALFA Laval and Westfalia separators.
- Condition evaluation and servicing of fuel injection valve, High-Pressure Fuel pump.
- Condition evaluation and servicing of cylinder head and piston.
- Remove and Re-fittings of Cylinder Head, Piston, Liner, Big end Bearing, Main Bearing.
- Remove and Re-fittings of Charge Air Cooler, Lube-Oil Cooler and different types of Filters.
- Prepared fortnight and Monthly reports and documentation to communicate with senior management.
- Adhered to timelines to meet quality assurance targets.

Sub Assistant Engineer

Mechanical Maintenance, United Ashuganj Energy Ltd. 200 MW Combine Cycle.

- Assist with Major Overhauling 16000 hours Schedule Maintenance Wartsila 20V34 SG Engine.
- Studied Power Generation Distribute processes to improve overall knowledge.
- Ensure safe, Economic operation & routine maintenance of the plant.
- Adhered to safety procedures and good housekeeping standards to comply with regulations.
- Maintained a positive work atmosphere by building relationships with co-workers and management.

2018-03 - 2018-12

2019-01 - Present

2017-03 - 2018-03

2021-01 - Present

2012 - 2017

2002 - 2012

2016-07 - 2017-01



Education

BSc in Mechanical Engineering

Sonargaon University

Diploma in Marine Engineering

Bangladesh Institute of Marine Technology, Narayangonj (BIMT)

Result: 3.35

Civil Drafting with CAD, Secondary School Certificate.

Pabna Technical School & College, Pabna.

Result: 3.35



Training Summary

Industrial Attachment

Orion Digital Power & Associate Limited (102 MW HFO Plant DPAL).



Specialization

Advanced knowledge of MS Excel, Word and PowerPoint.

Well familiar with Auto CAD 2004.

Honesty is the best policy that I can offer.

Ability to lead and other leadership qualities.

Endurance to work for long hours and under pressure.

Strong motivation and commitment to work.



Reference

Md. Eleas Hossen

Senior Executive Engineer (Mechanical Maintenance), United Mymensingh & Jamalpur Power Ltd. 315 MW Combined Cycle Power Plant.

Mobile: 01623-244600 Email: eleas.specific@gmail.com



DECLARATION

In the above circumstances, I hope that you would be kind enough to consider my application and provide me with any opportunity to prove my competence for the post.

Someon American Md Mehedi Hasan